I actually thought I was dead.
我还以为这次真的死定了
Shinpei.
慎平
Shide...
纸垂
Heine... no, Hiruko.
波稻…不 蛭子
You're worthless trash now.
对我来说 你现在就是个废物
You've shrunken so much.
你变得这么弱小
There's no way you'll recover.
已经恢复无望了
Your eyes are broken now. I'm just so disappointed in you!
眼睛也毁了 说真的 从刚才开始 我就对你失望透顶了
But look at your right eye!
不过你觉得如何 那只右眼
That is the observer's right eye. You must be the egg.
那是观察者的右眼 你果然是“卵”
You've just awakened.
而且刚刚觉醒
But why?
可是为什么…
When Heine looked, most of your data was corrupt.
波稻调查你时 你的存储当中 几乎都是损坏的数据啊
I didn't realize that had become what you developed into.
莫非那就是… 我就说你怎么会不断地在成长
I guess only someone like you were able to recreate.
也只有这样的你才能复原啊
So that's the power of love!
这就是爱的力量吗
If I can take your eye from you,
只要夺走你那只眼睛
I am going to get what I want.
我的愿望就还能实现
I failed to take it from Shinpei who had it in the fourth loop,
在第四轮
but I can take it from the egg who still has it.
那我应该可以从 即将赋予他人眼睛的“卵”身上夺走
If what he really wants is what I saw in his mind at that moment...
那家伙的愿望… 如果当时我所读取到的是真的
I'm not letting him get it!
休想得逞
Shide... wait...
纸垂…等等…
I can still do it...
我还能行…
If I eat enough humans, I'll get better.
只要吃很多人 我就能好起来
So come home with me.
一起回去好不好
Maybe take Ushioh's eye... and give it to me.
还是说把潮的眼睛给我
I don't need you anymore.
你已经没用了
What's that? Isn't Heine your mother?
你在说什么 波稻不是你的母亲吗
So? I don't care about the past.
所以呢 我对过去不感兴趣
Shide!
纸垂
And you call yourself human!
你这家伙 还算是人吗
But in fact, I need Hiruko to stay alive,
不过蛭子必须活着 否则我就麻烦了
because if she dies, my armor would disappear.
她要是死了 我的铠甲也会消失
I'll take you home, as you wish.
那就如你所愿 带你回故乡吧
No, I'm not going like this.
不要 用这副身体回去的话…
Come, observer.
尽管来吧 观察者
Let's settle the matter. Over there.
在那边做个了断吧
Ushioh! Give me Nezu's weapon!
潮 给我根津先生的枪
Shide!
纸垂
Shinpei!
慎平
Thanks.
谢了
No, Shinpei, we're being drawn in!
不行 慎平 会被吸进去的
I'm weak. Too weak!
我好弱 简直太弱了
Mortals can't go past this point. If you do, you can't leave nor die.
人类不能去那里 进去了就出不来 想死也死不了
You'll end up lost.
永远迷失在那里
But...
可是…
Let me go alone from here.
接下来我一个人去
No! I'm never leaving you again!
笨蛋 我决不会再让你孤单一人了
Dummy! Were you listening to me? You're so stubborn!
你才是笨蛋 没听见我说的吗 你个榆木脑袋
Ryu, can you hear me? Take Shinpei and go!
龙 你听得到吧 快操纵慎平的身体逃跑
If I leave you now, Sis will never forgive me.
我要是在这时候弃之不顾 到了那个世界 姐姐会臭骂我一顿的
Ryu.
龙
Sis made a promise with you, and I'm going to keep it for her.
我已经决定了 要代替姐姐 完成拯救大家的约定
I'll be Shinpei's support. I won't let him get lost.
我来协助慎平先生 决不会让他迷失
I'll follow your presence. Always!
我会追上你的气息 我会永远…
I'll be by your side.
在你的身边
I love you, and I want to be with you.
我喜欢你 想和喜欢的人在一起 有什么不对吗
Dummy.
笨蛋
Shinpei!
慎平
Sou! Take care of everyone.
窗 大家就拜托你了
Ushioh!
潮
This is Heine's home.
这里就是波稻的故乡
EVERLASTING NIGHT
《第23集 常夜》
The flow of time is cut off here.
到这里就没了 时间的流逝…
It's just like how Dr. Hishigata said.
和菱形医生说的一样
What?
什么
Time doesn't flow here. It's stagnant.
这里的时间不会流动 就像是凝滞住了一样
I don't think I can go back by looping. If I die, that's probably it.
就算循环应该也回不去 死掉的话大概就到此为止了
Ushioh!
潮
I just had her! In my hand!
我这只手明明抓住了她的
I know she's here.
她的确来到这边了
The shotgun that she printed hasn't disappeared.
毕竟潮小姐所打印的猎枪并没有消失
So she's within 50 meters.
也是啊 就在50米范围内
I can sense her too. She's on the move.
我能感觉到微弱的气息 不过她在移动着
Let's go after her!
我们追上她吧
Shinpei! I'm sorry. It's because I jumped.
慎平先生 抱歉 都怪我刚才那一跳
No, I told you to go after Shide with everything I've got.
不是你的错 是我说 要全力追赶纸垂的
This is nothing compared to what Ms. Nagumo went through.
和南云老师相比 这点伤根本不算什么
Let me control your body.
把身体交给我支配吧
I'll take on the pain.
那样就可以由我来承受疼痛
But then you'll be hurting.
那龙之介先生你不就…
I'll be okay. I'm a shadow.
我没事 毕竟我是影子嘛
I can tune down the sense of pain.
只要降低痛觉感受就行了
It's not just your leg injury.
而且不止腿上的伤
Your entire body is starting to give out.
慎平先生你的肉体已经开始崩溃了
If I don't support you internally, you won't have a chance here.
没有我的在内部支撑 身为人类的你无法在这地方生存
How does it feel? I'm going to move your body now.
怎么样 我要开始行动了
It feels strange. My body is numb, yet I'm conscious.
好奇怪 身体的感觉已经麻痹了 可头脑还很清醒
It's usually like that for me too, but being conscious only is weird.
平常我也是这样 不习惯只有意识存在 就会很不舒服
Yes, but it's kind of like stepping back. I can get used to it.
是的 不过和俯瞰的感觉差不多 还是能适应的
Ushioh!
潮小姐
Can you hear me?
请回答
Ryunosuke, is this Hitogashima Island?
龙之介先生 这里是日都岛吗
It looks similar to the sea, and the Wakayama mainland.
很像吧？可以看到海对面 和歌山的陆地
Yes.
是啊
Hey, Shinpei?
那个 慎平先生
I meant to tell you this earlier.
有件事我一直想跟你说
What is it?
什么事
You don't have to speak so properly to me.
你不用对我使用敬语啦
You're older than I am.
因为慎平先生比我年长啊
No, you're the same age as Ms. Nagumo,
不行吧 龙之介先生不是 和南云老师同龄吗
so you're much older!
你可是我的大前辈啊
Oh, no. I'm in middle school. When I died, that is.
没有 我死的时候才初中三年级
Ushioh immediately called me Ryu.
潮小姐都直接叫我“龙”啊
Well, she's extremely friendly to anyone.
因为那家伙是个社牛啊
I'm not the type who's super casual just because you're younger.
我也不是那种体育系类型的人 怎么说我也是后辈 不能没大没小的
Are you always so proper with anyone?
你对谁都是用敬语吗
Yes. I'm more casual with people my age.
是的 对同龄的人就不会
Then what about Mio? You're super casual with her.
那泠小姐呢 你对她说话 都是用平辈用语吧
That took getting used to.
那也是花了很长时间才适应的
Well, then. I'm gonna go casual with you!
-好 那我从现在开始不用敬语了 -什么
The way I speak is how I show respect. It doesn't mean we're not close.
敬语是我表达敬意的方式 说敬语也不代表我们关系很疏远啦
No, our lingo is super important! So please... uh... just do it!
不 这种事情形式很重要 我接下来不说敬语…对 我不说了
What's so funny?
很奇怪吗
It makes me want to get to know you more, Ryunosuke.
没什么 我很想多点了解关于你的事
Really?
真的吗
Look.
-万年青的白滨 -奇怪
It's Heine's ball.
是波稻的手鞠
Oh! Let's go after it.
-如果看到人形 -我们追上去看看
Roger that.
-那就是蛭子大人 -好
In red with flowers...
红色的衣服上开着花
She spins all the way around
咕噜咕噜地滚了一圈
Ryunosuke, see that sign?
龙之介先生 看那个招牌
"Store"... No, Kobayakawa Store?
“店商”…不对 是小早川商店
What...
什…
What are these things?
这些家伙是什么…
She spins all the way around...
-咕噜咕噜地滚了一圈 -是影子吗
Not sure, but they don't seem to attack.
不清楚 不过他们好像 没有袭击我们的意思
Ushioh!
潮
Ushioh, are you okay? Tell me what happened!
潮 振作一点 发生什么事了
Oh, Shinpei...
慎平
My head...
我的头…
It's Heine!
波稻
I promised Ushioh. Her body is a part of Heine's.
这是我和潮的约定 潮的身体 是从波稻身上撕裂下来的
If Ushioh loses herself and Heine appears,
如果将来 潮的自我消失 波稻出现的话 我就会杀了她
If I'm no longer around, Ryunosuke...
不过如果到时候我不在了 龙之介…
You need to keep that promise.
就由你来完成这个约定
Shinpei, I'm gonna shoot! I will!
慎平 我要开枪了
Okay?
你听到了吗
Shinpei?
慎平
Hold it, Ryunosuke. It's saying something.
等等 龙之介 她好像有话要说
She's different.
这孩子不一样
-She's not the evil Heine who killed you. -What?
-她不是杀害你的那个邪恶波稻 -什么
Her consciousness split at that moment,
当时波稻的自我分裂了
into the human Haine and Hiruko.
分裂成为 人类女孩“波稻”和“蛭子”
So who's inside you, Ushioh?
那现在潮体内的是？
She's the girl who loved sweets, Ms. Nagumo's friend.
是非常喜欢零食的女孩 南云老师的朋友
Her friend?
姐姐的…
Right. And she is also...
对 而且这孩子…
me.
我…
Haine wants to talk to you.
波稻说她有话要说
Will you listen to her?
你们愿意听听吗
Yes.
嗯
Thanks.
谢谢
Nice to meet you.
初次见面
So you're...
你是…
You don't have to be shy. They're Hizuru's friends.
不用怕 大家都是飞鹤姐姐的朋友
Okay.
嗯
I was in a long dream, in Ushioh's memory.
我做了一个很长的梦 那是潮的记忆
Sorry Shinpei, Ryunosuke.
对不起 慎平 龙之介
I got everyone involved, you, Hizuru, and Ushio.
都是因为和我扯上关系 你和飞鹤 还有潮…
Everyone died because of me.
大家才会死的
It's not for you to apologize.
你不用道歉
Hiruko was the one who ate me, and that's what Hiruko does.
吃掉我的是蛭子 不过那家伙原本就是那样的生物
Shide is to blame, for taking advantage of that.
可恨的是利用了她的纸垂
You're going to fight Shide?
你们要和纸垂大人战斗吧
We're in an everlasting night. It exists above our real world.
这里是“常夜” 是比我们 所生活的现世更高一层的世界
In an everlasting night, time does not move.
在常夜这里 时间不会流逝
Shinpei and Ushioh, can you see that?
慎平 潮 你们应该能看到吧
Yeah.
嗯
Now look at Ryunosuke with those eyes.
试试用那只眼睛看龙之介
You're right. I've been talking without lapse.
还真的是 从刚开始 我也能正常和你们对话了
That's why Shide wanted to bring us here. We can't loop nor see two seconds ahead.
这就是纸垂的目的吗
He's trying to steal Ushioh's eye here.
他打算在这里夺走潮的眼睛
The one with the awakened eye sees beyond the current world.
拥有觉醒后的那只眼睛的人 能去往比现世更高一层的次元
He will have control of the current life, infinite time, and space.
如果他真的做到 那现世的时间和空间都会任他摆布
It's like a three-dimensional person can do anything he likes
就像是三次元的人类 可以轻易把二次元的漫画本
Wow!
好厉害
Seriously? It doesn't feel like I can do that!
真的假的 我怎么完全没有那种感觉
It just awakened, so it seems unstable. You're in an everlasting night too.
因为你那只眼睛刚刚觉醒 还不稳定 而且这里又是常夜
That eye is at its best in the current world.
只有在现世 那只眼睛才能发挥真正的力量
The ending.
“结局”…
It's the thought that I saw when I scanned Shide.
在扫描纸垂内的真身时 有个想法突然闯进我的脑海
He wants to destroy the world,
那家伙打算毁灭这个世界
as if he's turning off the power after a game.
就像是切掉游戏机的电源那样
There's nothing after that.
在那之后不会再有世界
It's really the end.
是真正的终结
I know this sound.
这声音是…
Central military district information.
中部军区情报
B29s are headed north from the Kii Channel.
B29大编队正经由纪伊水道北上
There are 250 enemy bombers headed north in five squadrons.
约250架敌军轰炸机分为五批 经由纪伊水道北上
One has circled over Awajishima,
于淡路岛上空盘旋
and is headed southeast.
其中一批轰炸机已往东南方向飞去
May you Wakayama citizens live.
和歌山市的所有居民 祈求你们平安
It's the air raid siren!
是空袭警报
Ushioh!
潮小姐
Stay down, Ryu!
快趴下 龙
Ushioh, don't make a shadow on the ground.
潮 不要把影子投到地面上
The fire is dangerous. Keep your body at a minimum.
火很危险 把本体缩到最小
I'm okay! Shadows don't die here. This doesn't hurt one bit.
没事 影子在常夜是死不了的 这种程度不算什么
Shide!
纸垂
Nothing can touch me, no matter what you do.
你们根本碰不到我 只会在地上爬的蛞蝓们
You look like slugs down there!
再怎么挣扎也没用
Ushioh, first let me burn you to a crisp, then I'll take your eye.
小潮 等我把你烧成焦黑的不倒翁 就拿走你那只眼睛
So about what you were saying...
关于刚才所说的…
Shide wants to use your eye in the current world, right?
纸垂是打算夺走潮的眼睛后 回到现世使用对吧？
Then there must be a way to go back to the current world.
那就证明有方法可以回到现世
Shinpei, you're right!
也是啊 慎平
Kill Hiruko. Even in an everlasting night, you have the power to do that, Ushioh.
那就消除蛭子大人 就算在常夜 现在的潮应该可以消灭掉她
The everlasting night disappears with Hiruko.
只要蛭子大人消失 常夜也会消失 我们就能回到现世了
You got it.
那正好
But how? Shide is way up in the sky.
可是我们要怎么做 纸垂在遥远的上空啊
Leave that to me.
交给我
-This air raid is Hiruko's memory. -Stop.
-这空袭是蛭子大人的记忆 -住手
It's hot. I'm burning.
好烫 身体要烧起来了
Don't make me relive...
别让我
something like this.
想起这些事情
It's a memory?
记忆？
The everlasting night is linked to Hiruko's memory,
常夜与蛭子大人的记忆是相连的
although I doubt this is a past Hiruko wants to remember.
这一天发生的事 应该是她不愿回想的过去
Calm down. Even if it hurts, it won't kill you.
忍耐一下 再怎么痛也不会死的
Your pain gives them pain.
你所遭受的痛苦将会成为他们的痛苦
It's Shide forcing Hiruko to relive this!
纸垂…是那家伙强行…
Ushioh, jump at my signal.
潮 我发出信号时 你就冲出去
-What? -I have this memory too.
-什么 -我也有这一天的记忆
I can push it back for a little while.
我可以短时间压制住这段记忆
But beware of Shide's armor.
不过纸垂大人的铠甲
It works like an echo, and sends an attack right back.
就像山彦一样
To defeat Shide, hack him, and erase the armor first.
要想打倒纸垂 必须先用入侵 摧毁铠甲
Then we kill the inside. It's a two-step process.
再杀掉里面的真身 需要两步
But after the first step, he'll get to Ushioh.
可是完成第一步后 潮马上就会被干掉
No, I won't die.
不 我才不会死
Mioh gave me something.
我有泠给我的那个
Finish him off in two steps, No matter what, before my hair burns.
无论发生什么 我都会在两步内了结他
All right. I can buy you a few seconds.
好 虽然只有几秒 但我会打开一条通道
Do you trust me?
你们愿意相信我吗
We do.
当然相信
If Sis befriended you, you're my friend too.
姐姐的朋友就是我的朋友
Ryunosuke.
龙之介
Right, Shinpei?
对吧 慎平？
Yeah.
嗯
Thanks.
谢谢你们
I'm ready.
我准备好了 随时都可以
Yes.
嗯
Go... now!
就是现在
So I see, you got Haine on your side.
是吗 你们拉拢了波稻做帮手了啊
I'm counting on you, Ushioh. Stop Shide.
拜托你了 潮 阻止纸垂大人
Let Hiruko rest in peace!
让蛭子大人不用再受苦了
Leave it to me!
包在我身上
At this height, I can't get to Ushioh's body.
在这个高度无法捕捉到小潮的本体
They're fast and massive! I can't avoid them with my hair.
这攻击又快又重 我的头发无法完全防御住
I'll kill you even in exchange for my life!
就算与你同归于尽 我也要杀了你
In exchange for what?
同归于尽？
There's nothing inside.
里面没有真身
That means I can't even cross-counter.
糟了 这样我根本打不过他
So you read my mind.
我的杀手锏暴露了吗
He hacked...
入侵反弹回来了…
She revived herself? Did she eat a part of the original Ushio?
复活了？她吃下了什么 该不会是真正的潮的一部分
Then take this!
那至少…
What did she do?
她做了什么
The air raid stopped.
空袭停下来了
What happened?
现在是什么情况
She touched me to erase the memory of the air raid.
刚才那一瞬间的接触 把空袭的记忆消除了吗
-Shinpei, can you hear me? -Ushioh!
慎平 听得到吗
I know now. Shide's body is in the current world.
我知道了 纸垂的本体在现世
The current world?
在现世？
Shide is remotely controlling his armor using Hiruko.
纸垂通过蛭子远程操控着铠甲
If there's nothing inside, there's not much we can do.
他真身不在这里 我们根本拿他没辙
What does Shide's armor look like now?
纸垂的铠甲现在怎么样了
The left half is gone after I erased it.
被我消除的左半边身体没有恢复
Then erase the rest and go for the win.
既然这样 只要把铠甲全部消除 我们就能赢
Ushioh!
潮